Exercise 1.1

4 word(s) refer to a relative
These words are: wife, wife, mother, father,
1 word(s) refer to an illness
These words are: disease
3 word(s) refer to a science
These words are: mathematics, science", science"

Exercise 1.2

NOTE: in the following answers, types (not tokens) were used
In 33 case(s), the noun was classified in only 1 hypernym
One of these nouns is 'science', which belongs to the hypernym 'cognition'
In 1 case(s), the noun was classified in more than 1 hypernym
One of these nouns is 'algorithm', which belongs to the hypernyms 'event', 'process'
The average amount of hypernyms per noun type is 1.0294117647058822

Exercise 1.3

car-automobile 1.0
coast-shore 0.9090909090909091
monk-slave 0.6666666666666666
moon-string 0.5
food-fruit 0.2857142857142857
journey-car 0.09523809523809523
The biggest difference between the two rankings is the switch between the medium-level similarity and the low-level similarity.
The top level remains the same by a large difference in score.




Exercise 2.1

[('Augusta', 'O'), ('Ada', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('Countess', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Lovelace', 'PERSON'), ('(', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('December', 'DATE'), ('1815', 'DATE'), ('27', 'DATE'), ('November', 'DATE'), ('1852', 'DATE'), (')', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('born', 'O'), ('Augusta', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ada', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Byron', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('commonly', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Ada', 'PERSON'), ('Lovelace', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('English', 'O'), ('mathematician', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('writer', 'O'), ('chiefly', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Babbage', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('mechanical', 'O'), ('general', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('purpose', 'O'), ('computer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Analytical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Engine', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O'), ('Her', 'O'), ('notes', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('engine', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('recognised', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('algorithm', 'O'), ('intended', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('carried', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('machine', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('often', 'O'), ('described', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('computer', 'O'), ('programmer', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Lovelace', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('born', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('December', 'DATE'), ('1815', 'DATE'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('legitimate', 'O'), ('child', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('poet', 'O'), ('Lord', 'PERSON'), ('Byron', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('wife', 'O'), ('Anne', 'PERSON'), ('Isabella', 'PERSON'), ('Byron', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O'), ('All', 'O'), ('Byron', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('born', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('wedlock', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Byron', 'PERSON'), ('separated', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('wife', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('month', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('Ada', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('born', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('England', 'LOCATION'), ('forever', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('eventually', 'O'), ('dying', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Greek', 'O'), ('War', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Independence', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Ada', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('eight', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Ada', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('mother', 'O'), ('remained', 'O'), ('bitter', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Lord', 'O'), ('Byron', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('promoted', 'O'), ('Ada', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('interest', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('mathematics', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('logic', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('effort', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prevent', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('developing', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('insanity', 'O'), ('seen', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('father', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('Ada', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('remained', 'O'), ('interested', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('despite', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('upon', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('eventual', 'O'), ('death', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('buried', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('request', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Ada', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('described', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('approach', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('"', 'O'), ('poetical', 'O'), ('science', 'O'), ('"', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('herself', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('"', 'O'), ('Analyst', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('&', 'O'), ('Metaphysician', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('"', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('adult', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('mathematical', 'O'), ('talents', 'O'), ('led', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('ongoing', 'O'), ('working', 'O'), ('relationship', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('friendship', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('fellow', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('mathematician', 'O'), ('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Babbage', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('particular', 'O'), ('Babbage', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Analytical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Engine', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O'), ('Between', 'O'), ('1842', 'DATE'), ('and', 'O'), ('1843', 'DATE'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('translated', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('article', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Italian', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('engineer', 'O'), ('Luigi', 'PERSON'), ('Menabrea', 'PERSON'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('engine', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('supplemented', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('elaborate', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('notes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('own', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('simply', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('Notes', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('These', 'O'), ('notes', 'O'), ('contain', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('consider', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('computer', 'O'), ('program', 'O'), ('—', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('algorithm', 'O'), ('designed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('carried', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('machine', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Lovelace', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('notes', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('important', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('history', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('computers', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('She', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('developed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('vision', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('capability', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('computers', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('beyond', 'O'), ('mere', 'O'), ('calculating', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('crunching', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('Babbage', 'O'), ('himself', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('focused', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('capabilities', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Ada', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('mind', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('"', 'O'), ('poetical', 'O'), ('science', 'O'), ('"', 'O'), ('led', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('ask', 'O'), ('basic', 'O'), ('questions', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Analytical', 'O'), ('Engine', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('shown', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('notes', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('examining', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('individuals', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('society', 'O'), ('relate', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('technology', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('collaborative', 'O'), ('tool', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]

In exercise 2.1, not all Tags are correct. King is not an organization!
n exercise 2.2, the 4 tag class model is almost the same as the 3 class model.
So I have chosen to use the 7 class model, since it correctly classifies the word 'King' as Person.

Exercise 2.3

All tagged nouns:
[('Augusta', 'PERSON'), ('Ada King', 'PERSON'), ('Countess', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lovelace', 'GPE'), ('Augusta Ada Byron', 'PERSON'), ('Ada Lovelace', 'PERSON'), ('English', 'GPE'), ('Charles Babbage', 'PERSON'), ('Analytical Engine', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lovelace', 'PERSON'), ('Lord Byron', 'PERSON'), ('Anne Isabella Byron', 'PERSON'), ('Byron', 'PERSON'), ('Byron', 'PERSON'), ('Ada', 'PERSON'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'GPE'), ('Independence', 'GPE'), ('Ada', 'PERSON'), ('Ada', 'PERSON'), ('Lord Byron', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ada', 'PERSON'), ('Ada', 'PERSON'), ('Ada', 'PERSON'), ('Metaphysician', 'GPE'), ('British', 'GPE'), ('Charles Babbage', 'PERSON'), ('Babbage', 'PERSON'), ('Analytical Engine', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Italian', 'GPE'), ('Luigi Menabrea', 'PERSON'), ('Lovelace', 'PERSON'), ('Babbage', 'PERSON'), ('Ada', 'PERSON'), ('Analytical Engine', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('December', 'DATE'), ('November', 'DATE')]
